<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: thoughts | Just code it]]></title>
  <link href="http://billynyh.github.io//blog/categories/thoughts/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://billynyh.github.io//"/>
  <updated>2014-12-28T17:19:53+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://billynyh.github.io//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Billy Ng]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2014 Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://billynyh.github.io//blog/2014/12/28/2014-review/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-28T17:02:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://billynyh.github.io//blog/2014/12/28/2014-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Not sure what is the best word to describe this year, it was kind of negative, but I grew when getting through this.</p>

<h2>Personal Goal</h2>

<p>Well let&rsquo;s start with something positive. I set a few goals when the year start, and some of them are reached.</p>

<ul>
<li>5M downloads, this was the goal in 2013, delayed a little bit, still happy to make it.</li>
<li>Lose some weight. Although it came back &ndash;_&ndash; I did lose some.</li>
<li>This blog. At first I wrote weekly but then starts run out of topics (and time) and became one post per month. Writing helps me organize my thought and keeps me thinking.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Disappointment</h2>

<p>I take my work very seriously, it kills me to watch the team wasting time week over week. I spent quite a lot of time to think if it is my problem or not, I tried to give them benefit of the doubt as I was not involved in most decision, I tried not to blame people on not good at their job because we are a team. However, as I think deeper, I always came to the darker conclusions.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Are we really a team?</p></blockquote></p>

<div class="video-container">
<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/zE7PKRjrid4" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>


<h2>Moving on</h2>

<p>Making the decision is easy, the hard part is to handle it right. Turned out I was thinking too much, this year could be a bit different if I just trust my guts, but I learned a lot in the process. I would not say it is a waste of time, even though we did spend time for nothing for months. The more time you lost, the more you willing to make it right, and that&rsquo;s the power to moving on.</p>

<p>Your life is like a start up when you work in one, you move fast, you take risks. 2013 was a new start, 2014 was a process, 2015 is a whole new start.</p>

<div class="video-container">
<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/jEiTaIAj8bQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I failed to have side projects]]></title>
    <link href="http://billynyh.github.io//blog/2014/06/01/failed-side-project/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-01T23:18:21+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://billynyh.github.io//blog/2014/06/01/failed-side-project</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At the beginning of last few years, I wrote down a list of things I want to do through out the year. I finished some, gave up some, and some stays on the list. One of the longest staying item is &ndash; &ldquo;start a side project&rdquo;.</p>

<h2>What takes me so long</h2>

<p>It is easy to come up with something, but it is even easier to ban the idea. At first I thought maybe it is easier to start when I get more experience, learned more tools, but the truth is, the more you see, the harder you start.</p>

<p>For example, I come up with an idea of building an Android app that provide list of XXX and allow user to do YYY on it. Sometime I would not even start when I find that it is not easy to get the XXX list, or after I wrote some scripts to crawl the list, I get distracted in other idea and put down the started project, sometime you just get tired in work and decided to take a break in weekend.</p>

<p>Obviously I am not determined enough. But another problem I found for myself is, I start losing that kind of fire I had 5 years ago.</p>

<h2>Excitement</h2>

<p>Two months ago, I helped in a workshop for my middle school about using <a href="http://appinventor.mit.edu/explore/">AppInventer</a> to build Android apps, targeting F1-F3 students (12-15yo). When I prepared the material, the first thing I found is that, not surprisingly, the tool has VERY limited features. I am not even sure what I can build using that, how do I give advise to those students?</p>

<p>During the workshop, before telling them what the tool can/cannot do, I let them students brainstorm the project topics, and told them not to worry if it is possible, we can &ldquo;fake&rdquo; it. Turned out they came up with some interesting idea, of course most are impossible to actually build it with their skill level (or even mine) and with that tool. But seeing their discussion reminded me a very important thing, <strong>the excitement</strong>.</p>

<h2>Don&rsquo;t think too much</h2>

<p>People have different reasons to start side projects, for me, it is simple, just to keep myself motivated and do things that I may not have chance to do in work.</p>

<h2>Related reading</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://medium.com/busy-building-things/start-something-the-power-of-side-projects-648223f673af">Start Something: The Power of Side Projects</a></li>
<li><a href="https://medium.com/freelancers-life/side-projects-are-the-new-resume-a07e211240b2">Side projects are the new resume</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Yes or No]]></title>
    <link href="http://billynyh.github.io//blog/2014/04/28/yes-or-no/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-28T00:34:33+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://billynyh.github.io//blog/2014/04/28/yes-or-no</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>From being interviewed to interview others</h2>

<p>I have been working as a developer in different startups, I am not a decision maker in any of it, but as I becoming a “senior engineer”, I start getting involved in the hiring process. And this gives me a good view to see even we all called ourselves &ldquo;startups&rdquo;, different teams can have very different hiring considerations.</p>

<h2>Limitation</h2>

<p>It is obvious that hiring in startups is very different from Google. You don&rsquo;t have a large pool of candidates for you to choose, you don&rsquo;t have a HR/recruitment team to do that for you, you can&rsquo;t simply fly someone from another country and give him a few rounds interview even you know it is a fit&hellip;</p>

<p>As I mentioned in previous post, Hong Kong is not a good place for tech people, it is normal that the best people leave Hong Kong for better opportunities. Of course there are still many good developers or potential candidates but it is hard for startups to reach those talents. For some companies/industries, they believed in some kind of &ldquo;hiring season&rdquo; indicating that the &ldquo;market&rdquo; is more active and can have better chance to find match for your openings. I agree on the probability, but in my opinion, it is easier for you to find a match, it is also easier for the candidates and they may turned down your offer after all.</p>

<h2>Decision</h2>

<p>No matter what are you looking for, what questions you asked, at the end of the day, as a interviewer, what your boss/manager want from you are actually just scores, comparison to other candidates and most importantly, YES or NO.</p>

<p>At first you may feel pressure of saying no because it means the candidate will not get the job, especially you don&rsquo;t have much comparisons at that time. But in my experience, the more you see, the easier you say no, the hard part is to say yes.</p>

<h2>What the YES means</h2>

<p>For me, a yes means</p>

<ol>
<li>If the new hires will be working with/under you, you feel comfortable to assign tasks to them and believe they are/will be able to handle it.</li>
<li>You want to work with them.</li>
</ol>


<p>(1) is the bottom line, no matter how experienced the candidate is, if you think they could have problem picking up the existing code base, it is usually a easy no. And when you are interviewing entry level developers, you may have a lower experience/technical bar but you still need to have a feeling that the candidate is a fast learner to give a yes.</p>

<p>(2) could be tricky, you may think he is qualified for the job on every aspect but you are still not sure about if you want to work with him, could be just impression, the way he talks, his background etc. For big companies, you may just say no if you are not sure, but for small teams, we try not to lose any potentially good candidates. So far I don’t have a good solution for this, most likely I will just tell my manager that I think he is qualified but I am not sure on personality, then let the next interviewer decide that.</p>

<h3>Conclusion</h3>

<p>Interview is not just about a company hiring a candidate, it is also about a candidate deciding to join a company. If you are a big company, you could think that it is the candidates lost to not joining you, but as a startup, things are not working that way, at least in Hong Kong. If you want to attract good people to join you, you need to show that you have what they looking for, or something better than what they are looking for. It&rsquo;s not always about money.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Move fast and break things]]></title>
    <link href="http://billynyh.github.io//blog/2014/04/07/move-fast-break-things/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-07T21:45:34+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://billynyh.github.io//blog/2014/04/07/move-fast-break-things</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Who said that</h2>

<p>Mark Zuckerberg <a href="http://www.wired.com/2012/02/zuck-letter">did</a>.</p>

<p><blockquote><p>Moving fast enables us to build more things and learn faster. However, as most companies grow, they slow down too much because they’re more afraid of making mistakes than they are of losing opportunities by moving too slowly. We have a saying: “Move fast and break things.” The idea is that if you never break anything, you’re probably not moving fast enough.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>I totally agree on the idea. However, like doing startups, the idea is important but what really matter is <strong>execution</strong>. How do you interpret &ldquo;move fast and break things&rdquo; affects the direction of the team. If you are in the wrong direction and move fast, there is no guarantee that you can go back to where you were even you &ldquo;move fast&rdquo; again.</p>

<h2>Be able to move fast</h2>

<p>Depends on the scale of your product, there should be different way to move fast. For new product or just a prototype, you should collect user feedbacks, move fast, break things, <strong>get on the right direction</strong> as soon as possible. That is the speed you needed to survive in the industry.</p>

<p>What&rsquo;s next? You have some users, using your app everyday, but not yet the giant scale. To get more users, you need to keep moving and this is another type of moving fast. This time, you cannot just move fast and break things like the time when you start. From development point of view, as the code complexity increase, unless you have a good infrastructure, you will find that it is getting harder and harder to add features on top of it. When you add one feature, you may introduce two bugs, and slowed the app down at the same time. Beside that, there is a cost when you break things, maybe get some bad rating, maybe pissed off some users.</p>

<p>This does not mean you should not move fast, but you have to <strong>do it smart</strong>. You have to be clear on what you want to achieve from moving fast. If you want to try out new interface and get user feedback, it does not need to be 100% polished, but don&rsquo;t rollout a 20% done ugly version, all you can get is bad rating instead of constructive feedback about the new features.</p>

<p>I agree on moving fast, but I also believe in &ldquo;<strong>less is more</strong>&rdquo; (slow is fast?). At the end of the day, it is all about what the users want, new features may boost your number a little bit, but sometimes quality is what makes the users come back and use your app and not switching to other competitors.</p>

<p>Instead of running on your foot, isn&rsquo;t it better to get a bike or a car if you want to move fast?</p>

<h2>When you break things</h2>

<p>Please, <strong>fix it</strong>, before you break another thing.</p>

<h2>Reference</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.wired.com/2012/02/zuck-letter">Mark Zuckerberg’s Letter to Investors</a></li>
<li><a href="http://venturebeat.com/2012/06/26/facebook-hacker-stories/">Move fast, break things: Four stories for hackers from Facebook</a></li>
<li><a href="http://spectrum.ieee.org/at-work/innovation/facebook-philosophy-move-fast-and-break-things">Facebook Philosophy: Move Fast and Break Things</a></li>
<li><a href="http://mashable.com/2014/03/13/facebook-move-fast-break-things/">Are Facebook&rsquo;s &lsquo;Move Fast and Break Things&rsquo; Days Over?</a></li>
<li><a href="http://startupbitsnbobs.com/2014/04/04/move-fast-and-break-things/">Startup就是一窩老鼠</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The gatekeeper]]></title>
    <link href="http://billynyh.github.io//blog/2014/03/24/gatekeeper/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-24T23:11:56+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://billynyh.github.io//blog/2014/03/24/gatekeeper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Recently read some articles from <a href="https://medium.com/the-year-of-the-looking-glass">Julie Zhuo&rsquo;s</a>, she is a Product design director in Facebook. Although her posts are not about engineering, I still feel connected with most of the topics. I wrote some of my thoughts originally, but I think just put the quotes here is enough.</p>

<p><a href="https://medium.com/the-year-of-the-looking-glass/5c48db173662">&ldquo;Don&rsquo;t be a gatekeeper&rdquo;</a></p>

<p><blockquote><p>If you are somebody with an incredible amount of passion for high quality, you may be compelled to become a gatekeeper at some point in your life.</p></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>If you are a gatekeeper or find yourself thinking we need a gatekeeper, the thing that is broken or missing is trust. So instead of judging yes or no, good or bad, consider this instead: what could I do to make it so that I have more trust in the people around me?</p></blockquote></p>

<p><a href="https://medium.com/the-year-of-the-looking-glass/d0aa3b8af9b7">&ldquo;Why Designers Leave&rdquo;</a></p>

<p><blockquote><p>Every person who works in a creative field has an aspiration for her work, a yearning for that ideal plane which is the culmination of her taste.</p></p><p><p>When an environment fails, over and over and over again, to provide her with a means to follow her internal compass, then she will leave.</p></p><p><p>If you are in a position to influence that kind of environment, take heed. Lay the foundations for a space that nurtures, that yields the kind of work the best creative people can be proud of.</p></blockquote></p>

<p><a href="https://medium.com/the-year-of-the-looking-glass/bcddf7c85553">&ldquo;Quality is not a tradeoff&rdquo;</a></p>

<p><blockquote><p>Quality is a bar, not a tradeoff.</p></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>It just doesn’t work like that.</p></p><p><p>Why? Because to create high-quality work, there has to be a minimum acceptable bar. And high-quality creators cannot trade off below that bar. They simply can’t.</p></blockquote></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
