<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ui | Just code it]]></title>
  <link href="http://billynyh.github.io//blog/categories/ui/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://billynyh.github.io//"/>
  <updated>2014-12-28T17:19:53+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://billynyh.github.io//</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Billy Ng]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Quick look of messaging app UI]]></title>
    <link href="http://billynyh.github.io//blog/2014/08/03/messaging-ui/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-03T12:13:04+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://billynyh.github.io//blog/2014/08/03/messaging-ui</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I use messaging app everyday, whatsapp, Facebook messenger, gtalk, web and mobile. The UI of different apps looks natural to me and never tried to &ldquo;see&rdquo; the design of it.</p>

<p>Recently I am working on a messaging UI with a screenshot designer gave me. When I try to imagine how will this design looks like with real chat usage, I am sure there are lots of details not included in the design so I take a deeper look of the messaging app I used everyday.</p>

<p>When you received a message, you usually can see sender information (name / avatar), message content, and sent time. And for the message you send, you may also see deliver status (sent/fail/received/read), retry when fail.</p>

<p>Here are some elements besdies those basic thing.</p>

<h2>Date header</h2>

<p>To avoid displaying the date in every message, a common handling is to have a &ldquo;Date header&rdquo; to divide the messages, and whatsapp also added a sticky header for the date.</p>

<p><a rel="gallery-date" href="/images/posts/20140803/b-2.jpg" class="fancybox">
<img src="/images/posts/20140803/c-2.jpg"/>
</a>
<a rel="gallery-date" href="/images/posts/20140803/b-3.jpg" class="fancybox">
<img src="/images/posts/20140803/c-3.jpg"/>
</a></p>

<h2>1-to-1 message VS group chat</h2>

<p>In whatsapp 1-to-1, it only shows the name in action bar and does not include it in the content, it totally makes sense because you know who you are talking to when you are in that page. And for group chat, as more then one people you are talking to but the incoming messages are all aligned left, it is necessary to have the name before each message.</p>

<p>Facebook messenger also has similar logic of adding name but it is outside the bubble.</p>

<p></p>
<a rel="gallery-chat" href="/images/posts/20140803/b-0.jpg" class="fancybox">
<img src="/images/posts/20140803/c-0.jpg"/>
</a>
<a rel="gallery-chat" href="/images/posts/20140803/b-6.jpg" class="fancybox">
<img src="/images/posts/20140803/c-6.jpg"/>
</a>
</p></p>

<h2>Message grouping</h2>

<p>Most messaging app styled the messages with talk bubbles, it is interesting to see that some of them are not simply a bubble.</p>

<p>
<a rel="gallery-grouping" href="/images/posts/20140803/b-5.jpg" class="fancybox">
<img src="/images/posts/20140803/c-5.jpg"/>
</a>
<a rel="gallery-grouping" href="/images/posts/20140803/b-3.jpg" class="fancybox">
<img src="/images/posts/20140803/c-3.jpg"/>
</a>
<a rel="gallery-grouping" href="/images/posts/20140803/b-1.jpg" class="fancybox">
<img src="/images/posts/20140803/c-1.jpg"/>
</a>
</p>


<p>For Facebook messenger, I found that when continuous messages from same person is grouped, avatar is only showed once, in both 1-to-1 or group message. However, sometimes messages are not grouped, I guess it only groups messages within a short time.</p>

<p>For whatsapp, it groups continuous messages to one single bubble, my first reaction is it would be fun to write a list view adapter for that, need to have 3 item types for one message (start, middle, end) and the types may change when new messages come in, eg. end &ndash;> middle.</p>

<h2>Understand what&rsquo;s behind it</h2>

<p>It is easy to reference other&rsquo;s UI, but it is also important to understand why they handle information that way and even we will not handle like them, make sure we aware of it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Talks from Facebook, Paper team]]></title>
    <link href="http://billynyh.github.io//blog/2014/04/21/talks-from-paper/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-21T21:10:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://billynyh.github.io//blog/2014/04/21/talks-from-paper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>During the long weekend of Easter holiday, I spent some time on watching tech talks from Facebook. The newly uploaded &ldquo;Building Paper 2014&rdquo; series is really cool. Even I don&rsquo;t do iOS, seeing how they tackle the problems and share their approach is totally enjoyable.</p>

<p>Android and iOS apps may have different platform structures, but when your app goes bigger, most likely you will need another level of abstraction to handle large amount of logic, UI and communication betweens components. And when you want further performance tuning, you may need to go beyond the platform like what Paper team did. At that stage, although you are using different languages, the architecture will be similar across platforms.</p>

<div class="video-container">
<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/ZdiBPHpxGd0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>


<p>I also like the part about <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-KrF4bIofeo">contextually aware tutorials</a>, if you have time, you should watch the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OiY1cheLpmI">whole event</a>.</p>

<h2>UI details and A/B test</h2>

<p>Besides new talks, I also watched an old talk from &ldquo;Mobile Developer Day by Facebook + Parse 2013&rdquo;. Not sure why I skipped this talk before, probably because the title is so generic &ndash; <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e2w8z6mI47U">Mobile at Facebook</a>. The part that caught my attention is the A/B testing on their drawer to nav bar changes. It&rsquo;s not about what framework they used, not about how many users they put in the AB test, it&rsquo;s about how you see the numbers.</p>

<p>She mentioned that after changing the drawer to nav bar, the result in internal test is good, navigation experience is improved, users feel the app faster. However, when they shipped to 1% test, they find that users liking and commenting less, because users are kind of distracted by the nav bar notification.</p>

<p>This is very interesting to me. We do not have a very detailed metrics system on mobile (have some, but not detailed), I am sure if we do AB test like that, we will not be able to see the abnormal usage changes. This even put me in a doubt that what if we already did changes like that and we still don&rsquo;t know that?</p>

<p>This is like a regression test, not on code but on usage.</p>

<div class="video-container">
<iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/e2w8z6mI47U" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I see Android design guideline]]></title>
    <link href="http://billynyh.github.io//blog/2013/10/30/how-i-see-design-guideline/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-30T23:48:54+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://billynyh.github.io//blog/2013/10/30/how-i-see-design-guideline</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>To make a good Android app, the design is important for sure, but is following the design guideline enough? I am a developer not a designer, but still want to share some thoughts on current design guideline.</p>

<h2>Current design guideline is not complete</h2>

<p>Mobile app design changes very fast. To make the app stand out, people put lots of effort to stay on top of the design trends, they improve existing UI, and sometimes create new. And when the public accepted that design, it may become part of the design guideline. For example, navigation drawer (sliding menu) and pull to refresh. The drawer is now in the design guideline and is even supported in support library. Pull to refresh is still new but you can see that Google have their own twist and is using in gmail and google plus app.</p>

<h2>Case studies</h2>

<p>Here are some apps that I think they are in a good direction of expanding the design guideline.</p>

<h3>Dropbox</h3>

<p>I like the way they put the tab in actionbar and combined with the app logo. You can say it does not follow the design guideline, but in my opinion, it works better, and as long as the style consistent with the Holo theme, I would say it is a good design. However, I don&rsquo;t like they put the second level tab in the bottom, may be they can try using other style of indicator.</p>

<p><img src="/images/posts/20131030/dropbox.jpg"/></p>

<h3>Flickr</h3>

<p>Another UI I want to talk about is the slide up panel. I dont see many people discussing it, is it not popular? Not really. Google plus and Flickr are using it already. Comparing to navigate to another view, using gesture to drag out another view sometimes gives better user experience, you dont lose your current view and you have a chance to abort the action (slide out a little bit and close it back).</p>

<p><img src="/images/posts/20131030/flickr-1.jpg"/>
<img src="/images/posts/20131030/flickr-2.jpg"/>
<img src="/images/posts/20131030/flickr-3.jpg"/></p>

<p>While I write this article, I found that there is a new &ldquo;Photo&rdquo; app from Google in my application list, what supprised me is, the new share dialog. Beside the share dialog and action bar share provider, Google created a new share interface with the slide up panel. I like it.</p>

<p><img src="/images/posts/20131030/gphoto-1.jpg"/>
<img src="/images/posts/20131030/gphoto-2.jpg"/>
<img src="/images/posts/20131030/gphoto-3.jpg"/></p>

<h3>(Google) Play Music</h3>

<p>The fading action bar is very impressive and definitely will be a trend. In the app, it has transparent action bar so you can see the whole image, and when you scroll down, it fade in to solid color to make the bars stand out. For more detail, Cyril Mottier wrote a good <a href="http://cyrilmottier.com/2013/05/24/pushing-the-actionbar-to-the-next-level/">article</a> on this.</p>

<p>And beside fading, <a href="http://nicolaspomepuy.fr/?p=18">blur effect</a> is also coming. I think it is still quite computation heavy in some lower end device, but it should not stop you using it :p</p>

<p><img src="/images/posts/20131030/gmusic-1.jpg"/>
<img src="/images/posts/20131030/gmusic-2.jpg"/>
<img src="/images/posts/20131030/gmusic-3.jpg"/></p>

<p><img src="/images/posts/20131030/gmusic-4.jpg"/>
<img src="/images/posts/20131030/gmusic-5.jpg"/>
<img src="/images/posts/20131030/gmusic-6.jpg"/></p>

<h2>Keep changing</h2>

<p>Design guideline will keep changing. Limiting yourself in the guideline does not mean your app is good,
sometime you need to study your users and expand the guideline yourself.
Developer/designer should not be afraid to use UI that is not in design guideline, as long as it is good, it will be in the guideline.</p>

<h3>Futher reading</h3>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://developer.android.com/design/patterns/new.html">New in Android(KitKat)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.androiduipatterns.com/2013/09/googles-android-apps-look-boring-and.html">Google&rsquo;s Android Apps Look Boring &ndash; And It&rsquo;s a Good Thing</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.fastcolabs.com/3012752/four-android-app-design-guidelines-you-should-break">Four Android App Design Guidelines You Should Break</a>

<ul>
<li>(I dont agree on some of his points, may write another post on this)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/ManuelPeinado/FadingActionBar">https://github.com/ManuelPeinado/FadingActionBar</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/ManuelPeinado/GlassActionBar">https://github.com/ManuelPeinado/GlassActionBar</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/umano/AndroidSlidingUpPanel">https://github.com/umano/AndroidSlidingUpPanel</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
